すべてをのみ込む
究極のモンスターマシン ｢沼｣
The ultimate monster machine which swallows all who challenge it! The Bog!
Its gates slam shut with a force which drives men to despair!
絶望的に固く閉ざされたその扉
だがしかし 何としても
But! But!!! Against it, Kaiji and his ragtag band make their move!
それを押し開かんと動き出す
カイジたち
頼もう！
Come on!
さ… 坂崎さん
Sakazaki...
All-in Bluff
What's with that outfit?
その格好は一体？
The man known as Kotaro Sakazaki faces his final challenge!
男 坂崎孝太郎
今宵 最後の勝負に来た
明鏡止水　精進潔斎
My mind clear as water, bright as a mirror! My body purified!
天佑神助　寵愛一身
By the grace of God, I shall grasp victory!
これこそ勝利への道
邪念を封じ 仏のご加護
Seal away wicked thoughts, and throw myself upon Buddha's protection!
May the will of the gods and Buddha himself flow through my body!
神仏の念波 我が身に降臨す
わしは勝つ！
I will win!
ちょ… ちょっと
Hey, hold it!
フッ　また沼に挑戦するだと？
He's trying the Bog again?
Yeah, it's that annoying old guy again. What do we do?
ええ 性懲りもなくあのクソオヤジ
どうしましょう
フフ　まあ いいじゃないか
やらせてやれ
Let him at it.
去る者追わず 来る者拒まずだ
No sense in being ungracious hosts.
たぶん残った金の
持っていき場がないんだろう
I don't think he has any other idea what to do with the rest of his money.
全部 吐き出さなければ
収まりがつかない
He probably won't be satisfied until he's broke.
哀れなギャンブルジャンキー
Such a pitiful gambling junkie.
Let him try.
受け入れてやれ
はっ はあ…
Yes, sir.
分かりました　あっ
勝負 勝負！
C'mon, let's go!
分かったよ
受けりゃいいんだろ 受けりゃ
Okay, fine, if you wanna lose that bad!
フン
前回と同じく厳しい
磁気チェックを受けた坂崎
Just like before, they diligently check Sakazaki for magnets.
Seriously? After how much he lost last time?
おいおい マジかよ
この前 あれだけ
大負けしてんのによう
そうおっしゃってくださいますか
あっ そう？
Please! Give me some good news!
Thank you! Thank you so much!
あ… ありがとうございます
ありがとうございます！
何 考えてんだ
ヤバいぞ あのオヤジ
What's he up to?
The old man's gone nuts.
Amid the onlookers' misgivings, Sakazaki buys his balls.
見物人たちの疑念が渦巻く中
坂崎 受け取る
300万のパッキーカード２枚
Two 3-million packy cards!
坂崎 手持ち600万
リベンジ開始！
Sakazaki attempts his revenge with six million on hand!
バカな
No way...
こいつ 打ってない
He's not serious.
見せかけだ
勝つ気で打っていない
He's putting on a show, not playing to win.
この男 何を考えている？
What's he trying to do?
あっ 店長　どうしたんですか
What's wrong, boss?
坂崎の熱を直に確かめようと
近づく一条　だが…
Ichijou approaches Sakazaki to gauge his passion in person.
But!
I can't feel it.
伝わらない
はあ？
奴の体から勝つことへの執念
I can't feel any desire to win from him.
気迫が感じられない
そう思わないか？
No desire at all.
Don't you agree?
はあ　そういえば始める前に
He's been going on about putting his wickedness behind him since he got here....
何かもう 邪念はないみたいな
ことを言ってましたから…
バカが！
あるわけねえだろ そんなこと
That's impossible!
こいつらは死ぬまで亡者なんだ
Men like him don't let go of their lusts until the day they die.
But this unease...
とはいうものの この違和感
漠然とした不安も
何ら心配する事態にはなかった
This gambler's instinct comes to nothing!
坂崎は ただただ無為に玉を消費
Sakazaki fruitlessly empties his balls into the machine!
またたく間に300万を失う
In the blink of an eye, he loses three million!
カーッ　南無 南無 南無！
Amen!
敗北の坂を
まっしぐらに転げ落ちる
Sakazaki tumbles down the cliffs of defeat!
I must have been worrying too hard.
思いすごしか
開始から わずか７分後
In only seven minutes, Sakazaki runs out of balls having never reached the third tray!
３段クルーンに
一度も届くことさえなく
打ち尽くす　すべてを
あーあ いいとこないじゃん
Aww, that wasn't much of a show.
全然ダメ　何これ
A complete waste.
What's up with that?
終わりましたね
He's done.
分からん　燃えもせず
I don't get it. Was he playing just to lose, not even for the excitement?
ただ負けるために打ったのか
それとも燃えていたのか あれで？
Or was the losing what did it for him?
それとも まさか
俺の目がくもって？
Or could I be blind to what he's—
インチキ！
It cheats!
インチキ　インチキ
It cheats! It cheats!
やめろ！
この台はイカサマ… イカサマだ！
Hey!
This machine is rigged!
You! You're the part that does it! Die!
ここだ　ここが諸悪の根源
死ね！
バカ野郎　何しやがる この…
You idiot!
What the hell are you doing!?
放せ　放しやがれ
みんな 聞いてくれ
Let go! Let me go!
Listen up, everyone! This casino is a total scam!
このカジノは
とんでもないインチキ
This machine's remote-controlled!
今やっつけたこいつが
店の遠隔操作で玉をはじく仕組み
This casino's a ripoff!
ここは いかさまカジノなんだ！
インチキ…
Shut him up and bring him to the office!
黙らせろ！事務所へ連れてけ
さっさと立て　ほら
Stand up!
誰が行くか　今日は
このインチキ台と心中…
I've not going anywhere! I'm taking this rigged machine down to hell with me!
心中だ！
ああっ　ダイナマイト！
He's got dynamite!
死んだる　もとより
死は覚悟の上で来とるんじゃ
I'm gonna die! I don't care if I die!
死んだる　死んだる
I'll die! I'll die!
Anyone who wants to come with me, get over here!
死にたい奴はかかってこい！
なぜだ　こんな事態になっても
Even now, I can't feel anything from him!
まだ感じない この男の熱
I can't feel a real acceptance of death!
本当に死ぬという迫力を
死んだる　死んだる
I'll die! I'll die!
エセ　見せかけに見える
He's faking. It's just an act.
だが何のために？
金を要求するわけでもなく
But why? He's not demanding money.
これじゃ ただ注目を浴びるだけ
He's just trying to draw our attention.
注目？浴びる？しまった！
Draw our attention... Oh no!
おい　主任以外はついてこい
店長！
Follow me!
Boss!
安心しろ
そのダイナマイトは偽物だ
Don't worry! That dynamite's fake!
偽物？
Fake?
熱がなくて当然
No wonder he wasn't putting any passion into it!
He was just a decoy to distract us!
あのオヤジは 俺たちの目を
引きつけるための松明　おとり
He's really... No, they're really after—
奴… いや 奴らの本当の狙いは
やはりいたか　こそ泥が！
I thought you'd be here.
You thief.
こ… こいつ いつの間に？
When did he...
で 見つかったかい
お目当ての物は？
Did you find what you were looking for?
フハハ　残念だったな カイジくん
No? That's too bad, Kaiji.
だが特別に見せてやるよ
But I have something special to show you.
システムを見れば
諦めもつくだろう
Perhaps when you see our security you'll give up.
一条だ
Ichijou.
声紋確認　指紋確認
Voice recognition.
Fingerprint recognition. And a password.
そして暗証番号
この３重チェックだ
We have three separate checks.
金の壁 開帳
A wall of money is unveiled!
It echoes in Kaiji's mind! Money! Money! Money!!!
うなる金　金　金！
ハハッ　これが狙いだったんだろ
Is this what you were after?
うちみたいな高レートの裏カジノ
Running a high-rate illegal casino like this,
やる以上は
それ相応の現金が手元に必要
we need a lot of cash on hand at any given moment.
ご明察だ　とすれば その金が
カジノのどこかにあると踏んだ
And of course, that means it has to be kept somewhere in the casino.
You nearly forced your way into the office before to look for it, didn't you?
以前 半ば強引に君が事務所に
入ってきたことがあったな
あれは その確認だったわけだ
事務所に金庫があるかないかの
You were trying to find a safe there.
And if it's not in the office, it has to be in the manager's office.
事務所になければ
残るは この店長室
So then you set Sakazaki to make a scene and draw attention while you snuck in here.
そこで あの坂崎をおとりにして
我々の目を引きつけ
君はここに忍び込んだ
You were planning to find the safe and come back another day to crack it.
今日は金庫の有無を確認し
後日 改めてアタック
Am I right?
そんなところだろ？
残念ながら うちの金庫は
沼と同様に難攻不落
Sorry, but my safe is just as unbeatable as the Bog.
(電話の着信音)
金庫破りなど不可能だ
There's simply no way you'd be able to break in.
はい
店長　坂崎を確保したそうです
Hello?
Boss! They've got a handle on Sakazaki!
連れてくるように言え
はい
Tell them to bring him here.
Yes, sir!
店長　ありました
盗聴器とカメラです
Boss! We found a bug and a camera!
そうか　燃やせ
はっ
I see. Burn them.
Yes, sir.
Now, are you two ready?
さて いいかな ２人とも
覚悟は？
ひーっ
ほれ
It's your turn now! Eat this!
さあ お前もだ　くらえ
待て　殴るのはマズい
はあ？
Wait.
Don't beat him.
オヤジの方は
どうなろうと かまわないが
I don't care what happens to the old man, but Kaiji is going back underground in a week.
カイジくんは あと１週間で
地下に戻る身だ
His body is Teiai property.
つまり彼の体は
帝愛にとっては財産
If we're so rough with him that he can't work, we'll have to replace him.
あまり手荒なことをして
働けなくなったら
こちらの責任問題だ
On the other hand, we certainly can't just let him walk out of here after that attempt.
かといって これだけ
大それたマネをしでかした者を
何の制裁もなく
帰すわけにもいかない
どうする？
What shall we do?
わ… 分かりました
Understood.
Drop him.
組み伏せろ！
はっ
Okay!
お持ちしました
Done!
Excellent.
よし　フフフ…
何だと思う？これ
What do you think this is, Kaiji?
指折りか
ハハハ
Are you going to break my fingers?
言ったろ ダメなんだって
そういう手荒なマネは
I told you, we're not going to be so rough.
This is far, far more delicate.
これは もっと上品な物だよ
First I screw it on like this so it won't come off.
こうして抜けないように
セットして
あとは ここのネジを回せば
Then I turn the other screw, and the needle inside plunges forth.
筒の中の針が進むんだ
Then it tears straight under your fingernail.
ちょうど爪の わずか下の場所に
メリメリと
Are you actually going to—
貴様 本気か？
Come on, Kaiji. This is no time for jokes.
あいにく冗談は言わないタチでね
Unimaginable jolts of pain!
想像を絶する痛みを超えた激痛
何だ　まだたった１本で…
Oh, but that was just the first finger.
見ろ　世にも珍しい
爪の裏から塗る血のマニキュアだ
Look! How many men do you know with a blood-red manicure below the nail?
You're so lucky to have such a unique look.
こんなことをする伊達者
そうそういないよ
Now tell me!
さあ 言ってみな
何本 塗ってほしい？
How many fingers would you like done today?
Just keep walking!
ほら 歩け　ほら
うっ…
ほうら
カイジくん…
Kaiji...
さっさと消えな
Scram!
大丈夫か カイジくん
Are you okay, Kaiji?
うおっ　なんて ひでえことを！
That was terrible!
クソッ
Dammit! Goddammit!
チキショー　見てろ
Just look at this!
今に見てろ
Ichijou... Ichijou, you son of a bitch!
一条… 一条の野郎！
後悔させてやる
I'm gonna make you pay!
I'll kill you! You're gonna get a taste of your own medicine!
必ず味わわせてやる
俺と同じ苦しみ 痛みを！
うっ… いつか いつか…
Someday! Someday! Someday!!!
いつか！
Why were you so easy on him, boss?
手ぬるかったんじゃ
ないですか 店長
もっと痛めつけておいた方が…
You should have really taught him a lesson!
That was enough for now.
まあ いいじゃないか
今回はこの程度で
We don't want to accidentally kill him.
あまり本気を出して
死なれては困るんだ
あんなクズでも この地上ではな
Even trash like him can't be disposed of like that on the surface.
Of course.
奴が死ぬのは あくまで地下
He'll die underground.
手ぬるく感じるだろうが
この程度の決着が頃合いさ
It may seem like going easy on him, but it will have to do for now.
その数日後
破壊された箇所の部品が届き
Several days later, replacement parts for the Bog arrive, and it is repaired.
沼が修理される
どうだ？
問題ありません
So how's it working?
Perfectly.
The replacement parts are working just fine.
取り換えた部品も
スムーズに動きますし
The block activates properly as well.
ブロックも正常に作動しています
Then we start it up again tonight.
じゃあ今夜から再開だ
再開された後 カイジたちは現れず
Even after the Bog returns, Kaiji and the others do not come to play it.
坂崎のインチキ発言の影響か
他に打つ者もなく３日目
Perhaps due to Sakazaki's claim that it's rigged, no one else plays either for three days.
カイジが地上にいられる最後の日
Then, Kaiji's last day on the surface arrives!
沼のクギ調整 終わりました
I've finished adjusting the Bog's pins.
ご苦労さん　一服してゆけ
Excellent work. Would you like a cup?
Yes, thanks.
はっ　ありがとうございます
Everyone has forgotten about Kaiji!
誰もがカイジのことなど
忘れていた
It suddenly just clicked. Later, I'm going to go back—
店長！
Boss!
What do we do!? They're here!
どうしましょう　来たんですが
They're back and they haven't learned their lesson!
性懲りもなく また奴らが…
Kaiji? He's still on the surface?
カイジ？
こいつ まだ地上にいたのか
Yes.
はあ　確か正確なリミットは
今日の午後４時だったかと
His time runs out today at four in the afternoon.
フン
今 ９時だから あと７時間
It's nine right now.
He has seven hours left.
フッ　玉砕に来たか
玉砕？
Looks like he's going out with a bang.
Going out with a bang?
奴は地下を出る時 70万だか
80万だかの小銭をつかんでる
He came up from the underground with seven or eight hundred thousand.
そいつを使って 一か八か
He's desperate. He bet three hundred thousand on roulette.
うちの36倍ルーレットあたりで
30万張って
当たれば1000万
If he'd won, that would have been ten million.
He would have been able to pay off his debts.
それで奴の借金は完済
He wouldn't have had to go back underground.
地下に戻らずに済む
フフフ… バカが
What an idiot.
そんなに都合よくいかねえんだよ
Things aren't going to work out that well.
I'm disappointed. Even though it's his last chance, he's still relying on luck.
ガッカリだぜ　いろいろ
仕掛けてきた最後の最後が結局
そんな運否天賦か
What shall we do?
どうします？
まっ 見届けてやるか
Let's watch him.
最後の夢　あがきを…
Watch him squirm as his dreams die.
ようこそ　カイジ様の
この地上での最後の時
Welcome.
I'm quite honored that you're choosing to spend your last hours on the surface at our casino.
それを当カジノで
お過ごしくださるとは
従業員一同 身にあまる光栄です
いいのかよ
俺は問題児じゃねえのか？
What, are you going to treat me like some troublemaker?
あんな些細なことは
水に流しました
I'm letting bygones be bygones.
さあ ルーレットでもバカラでも
ご自由に遊んでいってください
Make yourself at home at our roulette or baccarat tables.
じゃあ…
Well then.
店長　奴ら まさか！
Boss, I think he's—
これだ　この沼をやりたい
Here we go. I want to play the Bog.
何 言ってんだ！
Are you nuts? The Bog isn't for broke-asses like you!
これはお前みたいな貧乏人が
手を出せる代物じゃない
I have plenty of money.
金ならある
5000万　十分だろ？
50 million is enough, right?
少しお待ちを
But...
Just a moment.
一体どういうつもりですかね
What's he planning?
Are you sure he hasn't done anything to the machine?
まさか細工されていないよな
この台
はい　24時間 必ず誰かが
あの台を監視していましたし
Yes. We've had a guard on it 24 hours a day.
カメラも回っていました
誰かが近づくチャンス
It's on camera too, and the power hasn't gone out or anything.
火事や停電のような
アクシデントもありませんでした
じゃあ なぜ奴らは
みたび突っ込む？破滅へ…
Then why are they trying it a third time?
Just to ruin themselves?
Shall we stop them?
ここは やめておきますか
100パーセント出る理由も
道理もありませんが それでも…
Even if it's rigged to be 100% safe....
逃げるのか？
Are you just going to run away because you think there's a little risk?
ちょっとでもリスクを感じたら
もう逃げ出すのか？
I thought this casino was supposed to be the home of the undefeatable Bog.
その程度か
このカジノの売り ｢沼｣ってのは
絶対的存在みたいなこと言って
底が割れたな
Ichijou. Act like a manager.
一条　しょせんお前は管理人だ
Shut it!
黙れ 貴様！
そうだ　その顔だ
That's what I want to see. Bring it, Ichijou.
こいよ 一条
まっ ここまで勝負を望むからには
You've got a lot of confidence.
何か魂胆… 策があるんだろ？
You have a trick up your sleeve, don't you?
正直 皆目分からんが
You don't get it, do you?
When a pachinko machine's set up not to pay, skill doesn't matter. Jack shit matters.
パチンコってのは一度
台が出ないと設定されたら
もう打ち方もクソもない
出ないといったら出ない
逆に言えば
If it won't way, it won't pay, You'd need to modify the machine to win.
勝つためには この台に
細工をしなければならない
Yet you haven't done that at all.
なのに その痕跡はないときている
どうやって勝つ？
How are you going to win?
面白い　逆に興味がわいてきたよ
Your strategy—your tricks—have me more and more intrigued.
その戦略　手品
いや むしろ勘違い
浅知恵といったところか
Or am I wrong? Are you really just that dense?
Very well! I accept your challenge!
いいだろう　受けてやる
その挑戦！
カイジ　最初で最後
Kaiji begins his first and last duel with the Bog!
沼との死闘へ動き出す
地上でのラストチャンス
This is his last chance on the surface! He has only seven hours left on the outside!
シャバで残された猶予
あと７時間　420分
420 minutes!
No sense in being ungracious hosts.
I don't think he has any other idea what to do with the rest of his money.
He probably won't be satisfied until he's broke.
Such a pitiful gambling junkie.